hey everyone welcome back to our Channel
I am back with another interesting topic
in the tosa automation
playlist continuing with our test
automation obstacle topic let's look at
our next obstacle which is called the
table search now this particular
obstacle contains a dynamic table with
rows and columns and here we need to
find whether a particular cell in this
table contains this particular value
which is 15 if it is present then uh the
value should be true if not then false
and accordingly we need to enter that
into this text field so this particular
table I can see there is 15 okay so I'm
going to enter true here and then the
obstacle will be completed so the same
thing we need to perform using tosa so
let's see how we can do this using tosa
so coming back to our tosa workspace uh
the first step as always is to create a
new module so we will go to our
obstacles folder here we will scan the
application and from here we need to
select just two elements one is the
table
okay and then the other is the text box
so these are the two elements which uh
we need to enter here and then I will
copy this and change the module name
here and then I will save it and close
it okay and then uh coming to the test
cases section so we'll go to our
obstacles folder here we will create a
new test case
and then uh we are going to add the
module
here so here coming to obstacles and add
the module
here now uh we have got a table and we
have got the text field right so uh what
we can do here is in order to find any
particular cell since this table is
dynamic in nature so this 15 value can
come anywhere right so any row any
column so the best and the fastest way
to do a search on all the rows and
columns is to use the constraint action
mode so we'll put a constraint action
mode on this value which is 15 and
depending on that it will filter out the
row which contains this particular cell
right once that is done then uh we can
go ahead and we can buffer whether this
particular element exists or not it will
return a true or false so whatever value
it returns it will be stored in a buffer
and then that buffer value can be
entered here okay so this is the whole
process which we are going to follow so
let's go back here uh and now we are
going into the table so we need to find
out the row and we know that the cell
value is 15 right so this we are going
to do a
constraint so that the row will be
filtered based on this
constraint and then once that is done
then uh we are going to say exist equals
equals uh the buffer name so we are
going to put this as bore
exists okay and then we are also going
to change this to
buffer right so it will check on the row
whether it exists okay if this cell
exists then it will store that in the
buffer whether it is true or false and
once that is done then we can come to
the text box and here we can enter the
buffer
value
okay so that almost completes our
obstacle so I'll change the bu state to
complet it and now we are ready to
execute so let's go ahead and execute
this in
scratchbook okay so as you can see in
the background it entered uh true
depending on whether that element was
present or not and it will enter false
if it is not present and the obstacle
was completed right so this is how you
can filter out rows based on the
constraint action mode and also you can
easily search any particular cell with
any particular value using this
constraint action mode and then you can
use the buffer action mode to U
basically buffer any particular value
based on some condition for that
particular row or
column that's all for this particular
video if you have any questions then
please leave it in the comments if you
like this video then please subscribe to
our Channel thanks for watching and I
will see you in the next
video